RESUME AVI GUPTA

Date of Birth: 2nd JULY 1998

Contact: B-512, STREET NO. 4, MAJLIS PARK, DELHI-110033 | +91 9899612959 |

avibilasgupta@gmail.com

https://avigupta2798.github.io/

https://github.com/avigupta2798

SUMMARY

I am an Engineering student who specializes in programming and working on specializing in data analysis. I am proficient in a few programming languages and some operating systems. I possess great team skills and am able to learn and apply new technology.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS

• Tools & Technologies: Git, SQL, Database Management System (DBMS), Object-

Relational Mapping (ORM), Shell Scripting, Django Framework, Python libraries, Machine Learning

• Operating Systems: Windows, linux distributions involving Ubunttu, Kali

Linux

• Execution: Time Management, Teamwork, Communication

• Others: Data Analysis, Literary Writing, Engaging Personality,

Creativity

EXPERIENCE

06/2019 to 08/2019

Web Development Intern | Digital Green

Delhi, DL

- Data Requests for Analysis
- Script Development for Automation of Monitoring Mailers for Data and Revenue reconcilation
- Market Price Information system

09/2018 to 11/2018

Student Partner | Internshala

Delhi, DL

06/2018 to 07/2018

Summer Intern | Jmoon Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Delhi, DL

- Provided Technical Support in testing open source hardware like Arduino, nanopi and dynamixel motors with sensors like magnetic sensors.
- Technology Used: Python, ArduinoIDE, openCM IDE

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: ProficientHindi: Native

• French: Elementary Proficient

EDUCATION

2017-2021 | B.TECH (IT)

Dr. Akhilesh Das Gupta Institute of Technology and Management (Formerly Northern India Engineering College)

New Delhi, DL

B.Tech: Information Technology

- Member of Alfaaz (Creative Writing Society)
- 8.1 CGPA

2015-2016 | Class XII

Sachdeva Public School

New Delhi, DL

Science Stream (Non-Medical)

- Minored in Computer Science (C++)
- Graduated with 91.6%

2013-2014 | Class X

Sachdeva Public School

New Delhi, DL

• 9.4 CGPA

ACHIEVEMENTS AND POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

- Intel Edge AI Scholar Udacity
- Active Member Alfaaz, ADGITM
- **Volunteer** Robin Hood Army (RHA)
- Web Intern Digital Green
- Student Partner -- Internshala
- Finalists HackCBS 2.0 by MLH

PROJECTS

Personal Website

http://avigupta2798.github.io/

A project designed for posting personal blogs/poems and representing work. A fine work of HTML/CSS for the first time.

Automated Mailer

A precise template to send a mail with the help of a python script. This template involve a html script for changes in body and add an attachment too.

Django Webapp

A webapp for authenticating and signing up the users. Database is created in MySQL and a simple html script for frontend.

Word Frequency Webapp

A webapp for scanning any provided webpage and counting the most reoccurring words ignoring the specific list of words.